# Czar Ian Curtiz Echavez

**Home Address** 

**Email** 

**Mobile No** 

Website https://czar-ec.github.io/

**PROFILE** 

Software Engineer with 5 years of mostly front-end development experience, with some experience with C++, Java and DevOps, with a keen interest in automation, DevOps practices, Machine Learning, Cybersecurity, and PC hardware. Demonstrated adaptability to learn new programming languages and tools as required. Relevant projects demonstrating these are showcased in the website above.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Web JavaScript, Typescript, Angular (5+), HTML, CSS (SCSS/SASS), Dojo, Electron

**Testing** Jasmine, Protractor, Cypress, JUnit, Cucumber (Gherkin), Pytest

Backend Java, C++, C#

**DevOps** Jenkins, TravisCI, Azure DevOps

Other Git, Python, Apache Tomcat, NGINX, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, npm,

AdobeXD, OBSStudio, OpenShot Editor, Inkscape, Figma

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer at Envitia (January 2024 – Current)

- Collaborating remotely within a team consisting of members from QinetiQ and Methods
   Analytics to create machine learning training environments.
   (https://github.com/Autonomous-Resilient-Cyber-Defence/PrimAITE)
- Presenting one of the machine learning training environments as part of the Black Hat Europe Arsenal events ( <a href="https://www.blackhat.com/eu-23/arsenal/schedule/index.html#yawning-titan-35706">https://www.blackhat.com/eu-23/arsenal/schedule/index.html#yawning-titan-35706</a>)

## Junior Software Engineer at Envitia (August 2018 – January 2024)

- Creating front end solutions required by projects, using existing company software / assets, and adapting said item for use in the project or creating a new solution entirely
- Integrated Cucumber/Gherkin into company projects to allow for Behaviour Driven
   Development
- Integrated Cypress as a replacement End to End testing tool for Protractor, which sped up
  writing of tests and improved debugging of tests when failures occur
- Created UI designs which were shown to clients before development which were useful in identifying the wants and needs of the client(s) – saved cost on development

# Student Demonstrator at University of Reading (October 2017 - April 2018)

- Assisting lecturers with marking and helping students achieve the objectives for the Programming module's practical.
- Helping students solve problems with both their programming and the setup of their computers
- After results day, news from both students and lecturers said that most of the 1<sup>st</sup> Year class achieved 60% (2:1) or above for the module

## **EDUCATION**

## 2015-2018

## University of Reading – BSc Computer Science (2:1 Upper Second Class Honours)

Final Year project (dissertation) is the development of an epidemic simulator system which simulates the spread of a disease around different countries. The system also includes a scenario creator which allows users to create more scenarios the simulations can be run on. **Achieved 70%** (available at: <a href="https://github.com/Czar-Ec/ZEUS/tree/master/ZEUS">https://github.com/Czar-Ec/ZEUS/tree/master/ZEUS</a> VS

#### 2012 – 2015:

# St. Wilfrid's School, Crawley- A Levels:

- AS: Computing (C), Mathematics (D)
- A2: IT (A), Physics (C), Chemistry (C)

## **SKILLS**

#### Communication:

- Constantly communicates with other team members to prevent merge issues / other problems caused by unexpected changes
- Able to convey work that is already done / needs to be done in cases of sickness ability to
  effectively carry out handover actions

### Teamwork:

- Capable of working individually or as part of a team and able to integrate new team members or self into teams
- o Able to use version control (Git) to be able to work in coordination with other developers

## Other skills:

Bilingual; can speak both English and Tagalog. (English as primary language)

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

#### **Portfolio Website**

Website referenced in the title. Acts as both the portfolio containing this CV and other extra items and as a testing platform for new tools or frameworks.

#### **PC Building**

During the 2020 lockdowns, I dedicated time to researching computer components and eventually joining PC building communities. This led to me building my first PC and since then, have built 2 more.